A Guide to the Papers of Willa Cather, 1899-1949
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series III: Correspondence
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1912 March 28], ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:49)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth] Sergeant [1912] April 19, APCS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:50)
    Two copies. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1912] April 20, ALS, 12 pp. on 9 l. (Box-folder 1:51)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] 1912 April 26, ALS, 6 pp. on 5 l. (Box-folder 1:52)
  - Willa Cather to Elizabeth Sergeant [1912] May 2, APCS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:53)
    Photostat; two copies. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1912?] May 12, APCS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:54)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1912] May 21, ALS, 10 pp. on 10 l. (Box-folder 1:55)
  - Willa Cather to [unidentified] [1912 ?] May 30, APCS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:56)
  - [Willa Cather] to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1912 ?] June 2, APC, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:57)
  - [Willa Cather] to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1912] June 15, AL, 7 pp. on 5 l. (Box-folder 1:58)
    Photostat with photostat envelope; includes AMs poem with first line, "The flowers of day are dead--" [Cannot identify poem's title - TN]. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Louise Pound [1912] June 28, ALS, 4 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 1:59)
  - Willa Cather to [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1912] July 5, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:60)
    Includes TMs poem (two copies) with first line, "Evening and the flat land," with autograph notes and corrections. Published in April Twilight as Prairie Spring. Photostat with photostat envelope. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1912] August 14, ALS, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 1:61)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1912] September 12, ALS, 5 pp. on 5 l. (Box-folder 1:62)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1912] October 6, ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:63)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1912] December 7, ALS, 4 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 1:64)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1913 January ?], ALS, 7 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:65)
    Includes editorial note regarding correct date of correspondence; photostat with photostat envelope. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1913] February 2, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:66)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Phelps [1913?] February 11, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:67)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1913 March ?], ALS, 4 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 1:68)
    Includes editorial note regarding correct date of correspondence; photostat. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1913] April 14, ALS, 5 pp. on 5 l. (Box-folder 1:69)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1913] April 22, ALS, 6 pp. on 6 l. (Box-folder 1:70)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1913] April 28, ALS, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:71)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1913] July 4, ALS, 3 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:72)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1913 August 5], ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:73)
    Includes photostat clipping, "The Book of the Week," regarding O Pioneers; photostat with photostat envelope. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1913 August ?], ALS, 4pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:74)
    Photostat. #6464-b
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] 1913 September 12, ALS, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:75)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1913] September 22, ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:76)
  - Willa Cather to Sara Teasdale 1913 September 30, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope (Box-folder 1:76A)
    #6494-y
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] 1913 October 11, ALS, 3 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:77)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1913] November 19, ALS, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:78)
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [ca. 1912-1913?] October 31, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:79)
  - Willa Cather to Will Owen Jones [1914] May 29, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:80)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1914 February 13], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:81)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] 1914 February 24, ALS, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 1:82)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1914 March 2], ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:83)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] 1914 March 19, ALS, 4 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:84)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1914 April 30], ALS, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:85)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1914] May 26, ALS, 6 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:86)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1914 June 23], ALS, 4 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:87)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1914] August 10, ALS, 4 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:88)
  - Willa Cather to Elizabeth Sergeant 1914 September 11, APCS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:89)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1914 September 28], ALS, 4 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:90)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1914 November 13], ALS, 3 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:91)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1914] December 5, ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:92)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1915] June 27, ALS, 6 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1915] July 28, ALS, 4 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Willa Cather to Miss E[lizabeth] S. Sergeant [1915] August 20, APCS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Willa Cather to Elizabeth Sergeant [1915] August 31, APCS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1915] September 21, ALS, 4 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Willa Cather to [Will Owen] Jones 1915 October 29, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Willa Cather to [H. W. ?] Boynton 1915 December 6, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1915] December 7, ALS, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1916] August 3, ALS, 4 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1916?] November 13, ALS, 6pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 2:10)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1917?] June 23, ALS, 4 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Willa Cather to Carrie Minor [1917] October 29, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:12)
  - [Willa Cather] to [Elizabeth Sergeant] [ca. 1917 ?], AL fragment, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:13)
    Originally filed with August 3, 1916 letter from Cather to Sergeant; "Information about place and McClung marriage indicates letter is 1917." [P. Yongue?]; photostat. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1918] December 3, ALS, 5 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:14)
  - Willa Cather to [Will Owen] Jones 1919 May 20, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:15)
  - Willa Cather to Viola [Roseboro'] [1919] June 5, ALS, 4 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:16)
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [1920 ?] August 22, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:17)
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins], [1920?] September 14, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:18)
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [1920?] October 22, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:19)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] 1920 November 19, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:20)
  - Willa Cather to Miss Emig [1920?] December 8, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:21)
    #6494-x
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Conklin [ca. 1920?], ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:22)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1920?], ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:23)
  - Willa Cather to Mrs. Stanfield [1921 January 6], ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:24)
  - Willa Cather to Mrs. [C.] Stanfield 1921 June 12 [i.e. June 11], ALS, 3 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:25)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1921?] July 6, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:26)
  - Willa Cather to "Dear Doctor" [Dr. Tyndale] [1921] September 21, ANS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:27)
    Cather's note inscribed at bottom of copy of telegram from Alfred Knopf; includes transcription and researcher's note. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Jones [1921?] October 1, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:28)
  - Willa Cather to Mrs. Stanfield [1922 June 10], ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:29)
  - Willa Cather to Henry Chester Tracy 1922 June 22, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:30)
    #6494-i
  - Willa Cather to Mr. [Maurice?] [1922?] July 30, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:31)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1922] October 4, ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:32)
  - Willa Cather to Duncan M. Vishonhaler 1922 October 20, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:33)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Johns 1922 November 17, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:34)
    #6494
  - Willa Cather to [Will Owen] Jones [1922] December 6, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:35)
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [1922?] December 6, ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:36)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Pitts Sanborn [1923 March 2], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:37)
    "Cather recovering from influenza at Lakehurst, NJ winter of 1923." #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Judge [Duncan M.] Vishonhaler 1923 May 23, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Folder 2:38)
  - Willa Cather to Judge [Duncan M.] Vishonhaler 1923 July 28, ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:39)
  - Willa Cather to Judge [Duncan M.] Vishonhaler 1923 August 1, ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:40)
    Includes an enclosure, Léon Bakst et les Décors de 'Phædra.' #6494-r
  - Willa Cather to Judge [Duncan M.] Vishonhaler 1923 August 27, ALS, 5 pp. on 3 l. with envelope. (Box-folder 2:41)
  - Willa Cather to Judge [Duncan M.] Vishonhaler 1923 September 6, ALS, 3 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:42)
  - Willa Cather to Judge [Duncan M.] Vishonhaler 1923 September 21, ALS, 3 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:43)
  - Willa Cather to Judge [Duncan M.] Vishonhaler [1923] November 9, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:44)
  - Willa Cather to Judge [Duncan M.] Vishonhaler 1923 December 10, TLS, 3 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:45)
    With autograph corrections and autograph last paragraph. #6494-r
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Liveright [1923] December 18, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:46)
  - Willa Cather to Judge [Duncan M.] Vishonhaler 1923 December 19, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:47)
    Autograph postscript signed. #6494-r
  - Willa Cather to City Editor, Omaha Daily News 1924 January 12, Telegram, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:48)
  - Willa Cather to Judge [Duncan M.] Vishonhaler 1924 January 13, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:49)
  - Willa Cather to Mrs. Stanfield [1924 March 3], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:50)
  - Willa Cather to Frederic Melcher 1924 May 29, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:51)
    With autograph corrections. #11082-b
  - Willa Cather to Mrs. Stanfield [1924?] September 4, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:52)
  - Willa Cather to Miss Lane 1925 December 21, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:53)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Glick 1925 March 20, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:54)
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [1925?] May 9, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:55)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1925?] June 23, ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:56)
  - Willa Cather to Charlotte Stanfield [1926] October 16, ALS, 4 pp. on 4 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:57)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. [Will Owen?] Jones [1927] March 22, TLS, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:58)
  - Willa Cather to [Will Owen] Jones [1927] June 26, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:59)
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [1927 September 13], ALS, 3 pp. on 3 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:60)
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [1928?] July 8, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:61)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Goodman 1928 September 26, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:62)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. [Stringfellow] Barr 1928 December 5, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:63)
    #7436, -a through -f
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [1928?] December 31, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:64)
  - Willa Cather to Father [Malone] [ca. 1928], ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:65)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1929?] October 2, ALS, 3 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:66)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Vance 1929 November 14, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:67)
  - Willa Cather to George Austerman 1930 September 14, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:68)
  - Willa Cather to Eleanor Austerman 1930 December 28, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:69)
  - Willa Cather to Miss Goldmark 1931 March 3, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:70)
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [1931 June 21], ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:71)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Wilcox [1931] August 10, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:72)
    #6494-g
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Meromichey 1931 October 5, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:73)
  - Willa Cather to George Austerman 1931 October 20, TLS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:74)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Flower 1932 May 25, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:75)
    #6494-u
  - Willa Cather to Huxton Marley 1932 August 21, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:76)
    #6494-aa
  - Willa Cather to Dr. Merores 1933 January 16, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:77)
    #6494-f
  - Willa Cather to Harvey Taylor 1933 January 16, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:78)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Mason 1933 May 21, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:79)
  - Willa Cather to George Austerman [1933] September 2, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:80)
  - Willa Cather to George Austerman 1933 September 19, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:81)
  - Willa Cather to George and Eleanor Austerman 1933 December, ANS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:82)
    With photocopy of frontispiece for "December Night: A Scene from Willa Cather's Novel Death Comes for the Archbishop." Photocopy. #6494-t
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [1933 December], ANS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:83)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Clemons 1934 January 27, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:84)
  - Willa Cather to George Austerman [1934?] August 26, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:85)
  - Willa Cather to Mary [E. A. Creighton] [1934?], ALS, 8 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:86)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Clemons 1935 January 10, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:87)
  - Willa Cather to [Cyril] Clemons [1935] June 15, ANS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:88)
  - Willa Cather to George Austerman [1935] December 3, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:89)
  - Willa Cather to Dr. Leech 1935 December 7, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:90)
    With autograph postscript. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Pat [Alfred A. Knopf, Jr.] 1936 January 19, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:91)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Dashiell 1936 March 9, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:92)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Clemons 1936 April 30, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:93)
  - Willa Cather to George and Eleanor Austerman 1936 May 16, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 2:94)
    With autograph corrections and autograph note. #6494-t
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Clemons 1936 December 11, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Clemons 1937 January 30, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Clemons 1937 April 9, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Clemons 1937 September 27, TL dictation, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:4)
    With autograph note signed by Cyril Clemons at bottom of letter. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Clemons 1938 January 28, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Willa Cather to George Austerman 1938 March 31, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Willa Cather to George Austerman [1938] October 9, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Willa Cather to Pat [Alfred A. Knopf, Jr.] [ca. 1939 ?] April 12, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Willa Cather to Dr. May 1940 January 4, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Willa Cather to [Pendleton] Hogan 1940 February 5, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:10)
    With autograph corrections. #10440
  - Willa Cather to George and Eleanor Austerman 1940 February 7, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:11)
  - Willa Cather to the Head of the English Department, Mount Saint Mary's College 1940 February 7, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:12)
    With autograph corrections and one typewritten page, "Willa Cather and Roman Catholicism." See also John J. Walsh correspondence, box 3 folders 66 and 67. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Miss Roseboro' 1940 November 9, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:13)
    With autograph corrections and autograph note at bottom of letter. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] 1940 November 27, TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:14)
  - Willa Cather to Miss Roseboro' 1940 November 28, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:15)
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [Mrs. Hugo Rumbold] [1940] December 1, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:16)
  - Willa Cather to Miss Roseboro' 1940 December 13, TL dictation, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:17)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] 1940 December 13, TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:18)
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [Mrs. Hugo Rumbold] [ca. 1940], ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:19)
  - Willa Cather to Miss Roseboro' 1941 February 20, TL, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 3:20)
  - Willa Cather to [Mary Willard] 1941 May 6, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:21)
  - Willa Cather to Mrs. [Ackroyed] 1941 May 16, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 3:22)
    With autograph corrections and an attached note by Cather's secretary. #6494-c
  - Willa Cather to Mrs. Ackroyd 1941 December 27, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:23)
    With autograph corrections. #6494-c
  - Willa Cather to Miss Roseboro' 1942 August 29, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 3:24)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] 1942 December 18, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 3:25)
    With autograph last paragraph. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Zo [Akins] [1942] December 26, ANS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:26)
    Includes attached magazine clipping with autograph note on clipping. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Mrs. Field 1943 April 19, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 3:27)
  - Willa Cather to Mary [E. A. Creighton] 1943 October 30, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:28)
    Autograph last paragraph; includes transcription; stamp previously removed from envelope. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] 1943 December 31, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 3:29)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1944?] February 5, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:30)
  - Willa Cather to Miss Roseboro' 1944 February 12, TLS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 3:31)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] [1944?] March, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:32)
    Includes researcher's note regarding date of correspondence. Photostat. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Halter 1945 May 24, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:33)
  - Willa Cather to Doctor Garbat 1945 June 27, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:34)
    #6494-o
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] 1945 November 21, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:35)
    2 copies: one positive, one negative. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] 1946 August 16, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:36)
  - Willa Cather to Eleanor Austerman 1947 January 16, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:37)
    With autograph corrections. #6494-t
  - Willa Cather to Father Maline 1947 March 3, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:38)
  - Willa Cather to [Mrs. Fields] n.y. January 3, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:39)
  - Willa Cather to Z. A. [Zo Akins] n.y. June 26, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:40)
  - Willa Cather to Mr. Griffith n.y. October 29, ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:41)
  - Willa Cather to [Will Owen] Jones n.y. December 31, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:42)
  - Willa Cather to Pat [Alfred A. Knopf, Jr.] n.d., "Saturday", ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:43)
  - Willa Cather to Miss Chapin n.d., ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:44)
    Includes transcription at bottom of letter. #6494-b
  - Willa Cather to George Austerman n.d., ANS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:45)
  - Willa Cather to Miss Simon n.d., "Sunday", ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:46)
    #6494-s
  - Willa Cather to Mrs. Mellen n.d., ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:47)
  - Willa Cather to "Dear, Kind Ladies" [Dr. Stacy and Dr. Moench] n.d., ALS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:48)
    Includes researcher's note regarding correct spelling of "Moench." #6494-d
  - Willa Cather to Doctor [Moench] n.d., ANS, 1 p. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:49)
    #6494-d
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] n.d., ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:50)
  - Willa Cather to Elsie [Elizabeth Sergeant] n.d., ALS, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 3:51)
  - Albert D. Donovan to Duncan M. Vinsonhaler 1923 November 26, ALS, 3 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:52)
  - Gilbert Monell Hitchcock to Duncan M. Vinsonhaler 1923 August 6, ALS, 7 pp. on 7 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:53)
  - Pendleton Hogan to Mrs. Alfred A. Knopf 1949 December 6, TLS carbon, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:54)
    #10440
  - Miguel Lamy to Cyril Clemons n.d., ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:55)
  - O. K. Liveright to Willa Cather 1923 December 17, TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:56)
  - O.K. Liveright to Willa Cather 1923 December 18, TL, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:57)
  - S. S. McClure to Osborn Lowell 1909 November 18, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:58)
  - Margaret Badollet Shotwell to Leon Bakst 1923 August 15, TLS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:59)
    With enclosure. #6494-r
  - Louise [Stegner] to [unidentified] 1940 April 10, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:60)
    Regarding Mrs. Alice [Gaudy], Willa Cather's high school Latin teacher. #6494-b
  - Stephen Tennant to George Austerman 1939 August 1, ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:61)
  - Julius Hilgard Tyndale to Duncan M. Vinsonhaler 1923 September 11, ALS, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 3:62)
  - [Duncan M. Vinsonhaler] to [Willa Cather] [1923 August], ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:63)
  - [Duncan M. Vinsonhaler] to [Willa Cather] [1923 December], AL copy, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:64)
  - [Duncan M. Vinsonhaler] to [Willa Cather] n.d., AL copy, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 3:65)
  - John J. Walsh to Willa Cather [ca. 1940?], ALS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:66)
    See Willa Cather letter, 1940 February 7. #6494-b
  - John J. Walsh to Willa Cather [ca. 1940?], ALS, 3 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 3:67)
  - Thornton Wilder to George Austerman 1940 August 15, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:68)
  - Thornton Wilder to George Austerman 1940 September 3, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l., with envelope. (Box-folder 3:69)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous Documents, Printed Matter
  - Receipt signed by Willa Cather for payment of poem, The Night Express1902 April 26, ADS, 1 item. (Box-folder 3:70)
    #5284
  - Willa Cather's comments on a book's binding [Alexander's Bridge] n.d., ANS, 1 p. on 1 l. (Box-folder 3:71)
    #6494-w
  - Carbon typescript of review from New York Sun of My Antonia[1918] October 6, AD, 2 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 3:72)